Preliminary Guide to the Elizabeth Hargrave papers, 1977-2010
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Elizabeth Hargrave papers 1977-2010
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Hargrave, Elizabeth.
3.7 linear feet Extent: 1576 Items
Elizabeth Hargrave is an Episcopal lay woman and multi-issue activist who served as the Chair of the Davidson County (N.C.) Commissioners, the N.C. Council of Churches Committee for Equal Rights, and Episcopal Diocese of N.C. Collection contains religious and activist conference and workshop materials, printed materials, clippings, a campaign T-shirt, one audiocassette, photographs, Davidson County (N. C.) Commissioner campaign materials, Charlotte Women's Political Caucus materials, and files related to public education in North Carolina. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
hargravee
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Elizabeth Hargrave papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2007, 2011, 2013.
Biographical Note
Elizabeth Hargrave is an Episcopal lay woman and multi-issue activist who served as the Chair of the Davidson County (N.C.) Commissioners, the N.C. Council of Churches Committee for Equal Rights, and Episcopal Diocese of N.C.
Collection Overview
Collection (2007-0120)(1500 items, 3.4 lin. ft.; dated 1977-1989) contains religious and activist conference and workshop materials, printed materials, clippings, a campaign T-shirt, one audiocassette, photographs, Davidson County (N. C.) Commissioner campaign materials, Charlotte Women's Political Caucus materials, and files related to public education in North Carolina. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Addition (2011-0109)(2 items, 0.1 lin. ft.; dated 2010) comprises materials related to the celebration of the North Carolina Council of Churches' 75th anniversary. Includes a copy of Hargrave's remarks and a sheet of digital photographs.
Addition (2010-0186)(1 item, 0.1 lin. ft.; undated) T-shirt,
Addition (2013-0031) (75 items, 0.1 lin. ft.; dated 1987-1990) comprises comprises organizing documents from a feminist group in the Triad, subject files on pay equity, women's health care, reproductive rights, and an academic paper.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Hargrave, Elizabeth; North Carolina Council of Churches; Women religious leaders -- United States; Feminism -- North Carolina; Photographs; Women in politics -- North Carolina
Contents of Collection
- Accession (2007-0120), 1987-1989, (5 Boxes)
  Collection contains religious and activist conference and workshop materials, printed materials, clippings, a campaign T-shirt, one audiocassette, photographs, Davidson County (N.C.) Commissioner campaign materials, Charlotte Women's Political Caucus materials, and files related to public education in North Carolina. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
  - Triad Literary Conference, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Women, Faith, & Health Care Justice Conference, 1988
  - Reaching Toward Wholeness: The Participation of Women in the Episcopal Church, 1988
    A 1987 action research study by the Committee for Full Participation of Women in the Church.
  - Public education files
  - N.C. Women's Caucus related files
  - North Carolina public education files (Box 2)
  - Conference on women's issues, 1983-1984
  - Photographs, (6 items)
  - Leadership in Action files, September 1988
  - The Davidson County Study on Aging, undated
  - Public Education Policy files, 1983-1985
  - Conference on Women's Issues, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Commission on Women's Issues, 1988
  - Political, campaign, and voting files, 1984-1989
  - Political advisement printed materials, 1977
  - Political advisement printed materials, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Charlotte Women's Political Caucus files, 1983-1984
  - Campaign T-shirt (Box 5)
    Shoulder to Shoulder--March for the ERA, May 2, 1981
  - Campaign T-shirt
    Bett Hargrave N.C. House
  - Religion, Politics, and the Media binder, 1986-1987
    Conference sponsored by the People for the American Way.
- Accession (2011-0109), 2010, (1 folder)
  Addition (2011-0109)(2 items, 0.1 lin. ft.; dated 2010) comprise materials related to the celebration of the North Carolina Council of Churches' 75th anniversary. Includes a copy of Hargrave's remarks and a sheet of digital photographs.
  - North Carolina Council of Churches 75 anniversary celebration, 2010 (Box 4)
- Accession (2013-0031), 1987-1990, (1 box)
  Addition (2013-0031) (75 items, 0.1 lin.ft.; dated 1987-1990)
  - Organizing documents from a feminist group in the Triad, subject files on pay equity, women's health care, reproductive rights, and a paper entitled, "Gender, Architecture and Institutional Self-Presentation: The Case of Duke University." (Box 6)